Daniel Haller

Website/Portfolio available at: https://daniel-haller.github.io/-_-

My published games are also available for free download at: https://dankdekuskrub.itch.io/

About Me

I am a software engineer who specializes in object oriented programming languages such as Java and C++. As well as a hobbyist game developer, 3d modeler, composer, and AI developer. I have a passion for learning new skills and love creating a fun and engaging environment.

Experience

Receiving Clerk | Cabela's / Bass Pro Shop | July 2023 - August 2024 | Green Bay, WI

- Unpacked and processed incoming merchandise, ensuring high quality standards
- Worked with RF and Zebra technologies for organizing and correcting inventory
- Managed online orders for both inbound and outbound shipping
- Demonstrated professionalism and customer assistance on the sales floor
- Assisted coworkers with warehouse item location and retrieval

Summer Staff Team-Member | Lake Lundgren Bible Camp | Summers 2019 - 2022 | Pembine, WI

- Facilitated activities for groups of 2nd-12th graders to provide educational and recreational enrichment
- Mentored and counseled a group of approximately 10 campers weekly, offering emotional support and entertainment
- Led drama classes, fostering creativity and improvisation skills in campers
- Collaborated with a team of 20 colleagues to ensure efficient camp operations
- Organized and led meetings with campers to effectively relay important information

Activities and Pursuits

Green Bay Global Game Jam | January 2024 | Green Bay, WI | http://tiny.cc/GBGJ2024

- Fully playable video game developed in Unity in a 48 hours time limit
- Managed a team of seven other team members to guide game direction and scope
- Setup and trained teammates on using software such as Trello and GitHub

Student Co-Project Manager | UWGB's COMP SCI 372 | February – May 2022 | Green Bay, WI

- Collaborated remotely with a team to develop an OpenGL-based game using C++
- Successfully created a playable version of Asteroids with efficient code implementation
- Utilized Agile methodologies, including scrum workflow and GitHub for effective project management
- Documented progress through requirement specifications and alpha builds for thorough testing

Volunteer | Lake Lundgren Bible Camp | Seasonal 2015 - present | Pembine, WI

- Completed tasks such as washing dishes, cooking, cleaning, counseling, running activities, performing, running sound booth, or counseling campers
- Spend weeks or weekends of my time joining a camp staff to enhance experience for campers

Youth Group Leader | Bethel Baptist Church Green Bay | 2022 - present | Green Bay, WI

• Facilitated activities and small groups for around 40 students weekly

Teaching Assistant | University of Wisconsin – Green Bay Programming Camp | 2024 | Green Bay, WI

Taught middle and high school students how to develop and create video games

Skills and Proficiencies

- Software Development
- Game Development
- Critical Thinking
- Project Management
- Communication
- Problem Solving
- Customer Service
- Java with 4 years of coursework experience
- C, C++, C#, SQL, and Python
- HTML, JavaScript, Bash, Razor, JSON, XML
- Organization Skills
- Picture Archiving and Communication System (PACS)
- Databases
- Teamwork
- Entertainment
- Design
- Blender
- Linux MultiMedia Studio (LMMS)
- JavaFX
- OpenGL
- Artificial Intelligence (AI)
- TensorFlow
- Google Colab
- GitHub
- Trello
- Pandas
- NumPy
- Unity
- Unreal Engine 4
- Bitsy Game Engine
- Stable Diffusion AI
- Sony Vegas
- Discord
- Open Broadcaster Software

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Emphasis in Software Engineering | May 2023 Bachelor of Science in Information Science, Emphasis in Game Studies | May 2023 University of Wisconsin- Green Bay | Green Bay, WI

- GPA 3.7/4.0
- Advanced Object-Oriented Design, Theory of Algorithms, Small Group Communications, Data Structures, Game Development